How is it?
Yeah, it's delicious.
Excuse me!
Coming!
Dai-chan, long time no see.
What? Haruko?
What is it, all of a sudden-
Rin-chan~!
Reina-chan?
Rin-chan!
Why are you here, Reina-chan?
Are you going somewhere else later?
Haruko?
No, Reina's here to play with you.
I see.
You see...
Reina-chan, do you like sweet buns?
What's that?
It's a round-shaped snack.
Then, yes!
Well then Rin, go get Reina-chan some barley tea.
OK. Let's go, Reina-chan.
We were just having snacks.
Reina wants to eat, too.
Oyatsu Fansubs Presents
Usagi
Drop
ashita no koto ha wakannai
明日のことはわかんない。
We don't know what's going to happen tomorrow.
korette gisei toha chigau. nanika ga chigau.
これってギセイとは違う。何かが違う。
This is different from sacrificing. Very different.
batsugeemu jan, nante omowanai.
罰ゲームじゃん、なんて思わない。
I don't think this is a punishment game either.
de, nande nanoka wakannai
で、なんでなのかわかんない。
But I'm not really sure what it is.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo,
ちょっと釈然としないけど、
In fact, I do feel quite troubled,
kimi no sonzai, ima daiji da, nantemonjanai.
きみの存在、いま大事だ、なんてもんじゃない。
Your existence is no longer so important anymore.
owaranai koto nante konoyo no dokonimonai.
終わらないことなんてこの世の何処にも無い。
Things that last forever don't exist anywhere in this world.
naku no ha tsurai nja, naino,
泣くのは辛いんじゃ、ないの、
Crying is a very painful thing,
ai no SWEET DROPS SWEET DROPS
愛のSWEET DROPS SWEET DROPS
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itaine.
ずっと夢みていたいネ。
How I wish my dreams could continue on and on.
motto yasashiku shitaine.
もっとやさしくしたいね。
I want to be more gentle.
kimi to iraretara, HAPPY.
きみと居られたら、HAPPY。
Just being together with you, I'm happy.
onnanoko tte tsuyoi ne.
女の子って強いね。
Girls are strong.
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne.
だけどときどき弱いね。
But at times they are weak
bokura no negai ha, HAPPY HAPPY HAPPY!
ぼくらの希いは、HAPPY HAPPY HAPPY!
Our dream is to be happy, happy, happy!
sonna hibi mo HAPPY.
そんな日々もHAPPY。
Those happy days.
JUST WANNA MAKE YOU HAPPY☆
Delicious!
Isn't it?
This is my first time eating it.
Here.
Thanks.
It's amazing.
Even though this is my first time here, it feels just like Grandpa's home.
By the way, what's going on, exactly?
You've got a pretty big bag just for a Sunday.
Oh, sorry.
Actually we... ran away from home.
W-What!?
Your family will be worried.
Why did you do that anyway?
Oh, let me guess.
Is it because of "that"?
What's "that"?
"That" is that.
Did your husband and you....
It's also partly that.
Also?
Also!
Did you and your mother-in-law...
That's also part of it!
S-Seems like it's really tough living together with your husband and in-laws.
Speaking of which, does a family that gets along well with the in-laws even exist in this world?
Frightening!
I don't have any siblings either, so I've got nowhere else to go.
Ah, your math textbook is the same as mine.
What? Really?
Can I stay over at your place?
You have to properly talk to them.
Let me see your other ones.
All right.
What about your in-laws?
The Japanese Language textbook is different.
It's all right. I already left a letter there.
Let Reina see yours.
OK.
But I didn't mention where I would be staying at.
I'll be the one to send Reina to school.
The rest... I haven't thought much about it yet.
I haven't told my parents yet.
Haven't thought about it?
You even brought your kid along.
Seriously, you.
But there's no helping it.
I only wanted to leave that place as soon as possible.
Even if it's only by one second.
I guess it can't be helped.
In any case, let's go buy ingredients for dinner.
Dai-chan?
The room at the right is completely empty. Both of you can use it for now.
It's true. They are different.
Thanks a lot. It's a bit heavy.
What exactly did you stuff inside?
Reina's slippers and textbooks are inside.
It's pretty incredible of you to run over here with this.
You probably eat "that" normally.
I'll cook you something proper.
I don't eat "that".
Daikichi, can we go and look at some snacks?
Yes, but one of each only.
Yes~!
Which type of meat should I choose?
They're all the same.
That won't do. This one.
But... this one is also...
Oh, Daikichi-san, hello.
Dai-chan, this meat is so cheap.
Shit!
No, this isn't what you think it is.
Her name is Haruko; a cousin from my mother's side.
Does it matter which side I'm from?
I-I see, so that's who she is.
Nice to meet you.
My son and Rin-chan are good friends.
Why am I blabbering like an idiot when she didn't even ask?
Besides, what position am I in that I have to be explaining myself to her?
What's with "it's not what you think it is"?!
My name's Reina.
She's already a first year elementary school student starting this year.
I'm Kouki.
Yo, Kouki.
What snack did you get?
Oh, Daikichi. I got this one.
DX Big Nyan Gum.
Mine is vegetable sponge cakes.
Reina got Nyan Nyan Kororin mascot's candy.
Is that really a snack?
She's a really beautiful person.
W-Well, she's beautiful for a mother.
But I feel it's best not to commit adultery.
Y-You idiot!
It's totally not like that.
Besides, there's only Kouki and her in the family. It's tough for them.
I never once thought of that.
Both?
You moron! You've watched too many weird soap dramas.
She's at most only older than us by two or three years.
H-How do I know how old she is?
Hey, she probably divorced.
I'm not very sure.
Looks delicious.
I've never eaten this before.
I tried cooking something different.
Normally, I always prioritise my mother-in-law's favourite food.
Mama, make this at home too.
All right then, itadakimasu!
Itadakimasu~!
Delicious.
Why thank you, Rin-chan.
Hey, Reina, hold your chopsticks properly.
Yes~!
The floor is making squishy squishy sounds.
That's enough Reina, take this towel.
Yes!
What's that?
Oh, a bra~
Hey, Reina! Stop pulling so hard.
She fell asleep?
Yeah, finally.
Both of them are too excited.
I already carried Rin-chan over to your futon.
Thank you.
Here.
Thanks.
It's great! It's been a long time since I had beer.
Do you want something to eat?
I've become fat recently, so forget it.
I see, that's right.
What? Have I really grown fat?
No, it's very normal for a thirty year old.
After approaching thirty...
Everything changes once you hit thirty.
I'd better be careful.
Though I say this, my husband doesn't even look at me.
Who am I working so hard for to maintain this figure?
Haruko.
Yeah?
When you two were taking a bath just now, I gave a call to them.
What? Why did you!
I'm warning you, don't do weird things, Dai-chan!
What's weird about that?
They'll be worried.
I only told them that both of you are doing fine,
and that you're only staying at my house temporarily. That's all.
I didn't even mention my address.
I already left a letter before running out.
Mind your own business!
No, I'm fine with you.
But the problem is Reina.
Reina is with me.
She's also really healthy.
Isn't that OK?
Even so, if you don't tell them properly where Reina is, even if she's healthy...
I think anyone waiting won't know she's all right.
Why bother thinking about them?
Calm down a bit, will you?
Rin-chan.
You're only trying to make them worried.
Come here.
This is Reina's nose.
Papa and Mama are always fighting.
Even though they're married?
Yeah, even though they are married. Reina always pretends to sleep by burying herself in the blanket.
Let's hold hands.
It's itchy.
That's my face.
I... day after day...
I have been hiding my feelings ever since I got married.
What's wrong with making them worried for a bit?
I'm sorry, Dai-chan.
I'm saying strange things.
It's fine.
I'm going to sleep.
OK.
Dai-chan.
Dai-chan, good night.
Good night.
Rin-chan?
Good morning.
Are you making breakfast?
Yup.
Oh, Daikichi, good morning.
You're up rather early today.
Yeah, sort of.
Hey Dai-chan!
You have Rin-chan make breakfast?
D-Don't take me for an idiot!
It's always been the two of us making breakfast together.
When it's time to use the stove, I-
Get along with each other!
Come look at you, the rice are all over your face.
Eh~?
Hurry up and eat.
We're going to take the train to school.
Rin-chan~! Rin-chan~!
Who is it this early?
It's Kouki-kun.
I hear you already!
Stop shouting and just come in.
You're disturbing the neighbours!
Rin-chan, is your school very far?
Going off so early.
Nope.
Kouki-kun's mother is too busy, so he comes over to our place in the morning first.
G-Good morning.
Daikichi, you got married!
I did not! She's my cousin.
What's with that?
You're not married, after all.
What do you mean, "after all"?
Daikichi, do you want to get married?
What?  No... That's why...
Mama, being single is better, right?
What's a single?
Means not marrying.
I know, it's divorce.
I don't know what's a divorce.
Reina-chan's mother, who's married, thinks being single is better.
Daikichi, who's single, thinks getting married is better?
Grown-ups are so weird.
Yeah, they are weird indeed.
Daikichi, can I have some rice balls?
You have eaten, right?
Yeah.
Fine then, go ahead.
That's my portion, you know.
That's great!
Didn't you have breakfast?
Why are you eating here?
Just how nice a guy do you want to be, Dai-chan?
What's wrong with it?
What? It's just a rice ball.
I'm not referring to that.
You're also very busy yourself.
That beautiful mother, you're indeed...
Id-Id-You idiot!
You're going on about that again!?
I only want lend her a helping hand.
Rin and the both of them are rather close.
But it's only that.
I don't really know the details, but Kouki and his mother definitely went through some rough patches.
It'll be very rude of me to probe too much into it.
I guess being a single mother is really tough.
Reina! Didn't I say that you'll be late if you don't hurry up?
Haruko?
Mama's going on ahead, you know.
Good morning!
Yes, good morning.
Keep it a secret that we're staying at someone's place.
What? But why?
Don't ask why, got it?
Yes~!
Good morning!
You came with your mother?
Yeah, that's right.
Because we ran away from home secretly.
So we took the train today.
What? What do you mean?
No, stop! Hey~!
Didn't I tell you to hold onto it tightly?
It can't be gotten back.
But it could have flew back to its home.
That's right, it's possible.
Good work!
Oh? You're pretty late today.
Yeah, my family is helping to look after my kid.
Is Yuu-kun doing well?
Yeah, never been better.
He's so lively recently that even I can't handle him.
But isn't it great that your husband is willing to help?
This is only the first time.
He just happened to be back from a business trip and is taking a break.
Besides, husbands can't be counted on to raise a child.
Hurry, hurry!
Reina-chan is waiting.
Yes ma'am.
I'm back, Reina-chan~!
She fell asleep very quickly today.
Haruko, you're not thinking of making this into a big deal, are you?
Are you referring to a divorce?
Yeah, that's right.
No, I won't.
It's not like that.
I see, I worried for nothing.
Well, I have thought about that many times before.
Or should I say I think about it almost everyday.
Well, I'm seeing my husband as an enemy at their place...
Everyone else is an enemy other than Reina.
I always felt that only both of us are family.
But you know, divorce is very unrealistic to me.
Thinking about Reina, and my ability to earn.
And divorce comes with many troublesome things before it can be achieved.
The conclusion I came to is that my current situation seems to be better.
I decided to get married just after I started working.
Because at that time, all I thought of was how to be a good wife.
That's only all I have.
This is the only way to protect Reina.
I've never once thought of getting married.
But looks like even a normal family is complicated.
You managed to settle everything on your own, that's really impressive.
It's nothing.
I didn't even do anything for her.
That's not true.
Rin-chan looks really happy to me.
She even cooks for you.
Kouki-kun's family is working hard, too.
It'll be fine for both Reina and I.
You've been saying the both of you.
Have you properly talked this over with your husband?
He's always working overtime. We hardly have any time to talk.
That's why, I've to work hard together with Reina.
Besides, I've been enduring it for so many years.
It shouldn't be a problem in the future.
As long as I don't think too much, I don't think it's a problem to just carry on living.
Very unhealthy.
It's the opposite!
Your body will spoil if this were not the case.
You've gotten really strong, Haruko.
Well, I guess so.
When you have a child, you have to develop the courage to help them when the need arises.
Especially when the child is still a baby.
Well, I don't really understand when it's still a baby.
After going through such a lifestyle again and again,
you sort of slowly change to become like this.
I hate this, becoming an aunty.
I never even thought of becoming strong.
If I had a choice, I'd really wish to be a little girl forever.
I'm sorry, Dai-chan. Thanks.
I'll go home tomorrow.
I see.
Just does it mean to be married?
And what does it mean to become a parent?
What's wrong? It's your turn, Reina.
What's wrong?
Yeah, I was right.
About what?
It's Papa's car.
Your Papa will only come after work.
It's impossible for him to be here so early.
It's definitely Papa.
Reina can't be wrong about it!
Seriously, I tell you it's not him, Reina!
What?
Papa!
I was so worried, Reina.
Reina was also worried.
I'm sorry.
What's with that?
It's possible for him to come back at such an early time if he wants to.
Hey! Don't say such things.
It's very tough working at a company.
Hideyuki-san, you idiot.
I'm really sorry.
Haruko must have given you lots of trouble.
N-No, it's nothing.
I didn't do anything much.
I didn't even change my clothes.
Thank you very much, Dai-chan.
It'll be great if your Papa helps in carrying the luggage.
Not a bit considerate at all.
That's right, not considerate at all.
You can come again any time you feel like it.
How could I? I can't impose on you any more.
That's not what I mean.
I'm saying Rin wants to meet Reina-chan.
Thanks a lot, Dai-chan.
Mama, why don't we come over on Sunday?
Hey, Reina.
The Haruko who was always crying when she was young.
The sobbing Haruko yesterday who said she wants to be a girl forever.
Well then.
Next time, bring less luggage when you come.
I can't bear to see it any longer.
Impossible, impossible.
A woman always has lots of luggage.
This amount is nothing at all.
Bye bye.
I'll send you two off!
nichiyou no hare ta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
On a clear Sunday afternoon
kyou ha doko he yukou
今日はどこへ行こう
Where are we heading today?
kayoi nareta itsumono michi ga mabushiku kagayaite mieru
通いなれたいつもの道が　まぶしく輝いて見える
The usual road that we always take seems to be shining radiantly
terasu atatakai taiyou to tonari ni kimi ga ireba
照らすあたたかい太陽と　となりに君がいれば
The warm sun is shining with you still by my side
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
While we're feeling so merry
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe ha doko made mo
声はどこまでも
Our voices are everywhere
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
maiagaru kaze ni nori
まいあがる風にのり
Riding on the soaring wind
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe mo tobi haneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Our voices are hopping too
What do you think of this?
But this one seems to suit Rin-chan more.
Look, how's this?
Can I also try this on for a look?
Sure, go ahead.
I'm thirsty!
Only the fitting is left.
This one looks good too!
Erm... Kouki and I will shop around elsewhere first.
Sure~!
Look, it suits you perfectly.
Rin-chan looks so cute.
Is it good?
This must be the summer flavour.
Yeah.